JU LIN

 $+64 \cdot 027 \cdot 545 \cdot 3988 \diamond$ soasme@gmail.com GitHub - @soasme \diamond blog - enqueuezero.com

SUMMARY

Ju Lin has a wide knowledge of DevOps, Web Programming, and System Administration. He is an expert in Python Programming, Operating System, and Kubernetes. He likes provisioning cloud resources by Infrastructure as Code. He is a passionate learner with endless curiosity and enjoys jumping out of the comfort zone.

EXPERIENCE

Workday Senior DevOps Engineer Mar 2017 -

Auckland, New Zealand

- · Developed and maintained a statuspage-like API and command line tools. It has provided health data for all customer-facing services over 10+ data centers for a statuspage product. Outage is rare.
- · Developed and maintained a continuous delivery pipeline, using Jenkins and Chef. The applications were packaged into formats such as RPM, wheel, etc. A set of chef recipes is responsible for configuring CentOS, managing system services, setup monitoring agents, etc on bare metals.
- · Maintained a fleet of AWS resources via Terraform. Inside the VPC, there are a VPC with public and private subnets in 3 availability zones, ALB with security groups attached, NAT gateway, internet gateway, certificates issued by ACM, domain names in Route53, a transit gateway tunneling back to private cloud data centers, etc.
- · Developed and maintained a Kubernetes cluster using EKS, with EC2 in private subnets as worker nodes. A fleet of applications such as Redis, PostgreSQL, InfluxDB, React Applications run on it. They're managed by Kubernetes YAMLs using resources such as Deployment, DeamonSet, ConfigMap, PVC, Ingress, etc.
- · Worked with internal operation centers to perform level-1 triage on critical incidents. Built monitoring dashboards and time series queries providing more insights into the production environments.

Lipinshuo, Inc

May 2015 - September 2016

Beijing, China

Tech Lead, Software Engineer

- · Project leadership and management. Capable of leading high performing teams under tough deadlines, to meet expectations of multiple customers externally or internally.
- · System administration. Maintained configurations for Nginx, supervisord, gunicorn, etc.
- · System architecture. Developed gateway and message queue applications to improve both the scale and the performance of the entire system.
- · Continuous Delivery. Wrote packaging tool Beeper and deploying tool Fapistrano.
- · Migrated image format from JPEG to WEBP. Reduced CDN bandwidth by 75%.
- · Developed a fully functional e-shop web application that drove 1k+ orders everyday.
- · Developed a spider application to scrap production information in other websites.

Douban Read

April 2013 - March 2015 Beijing, China

Product Development Engineer

- · Designed and implemented a new version of robust, testable, document-autogen APIs. Reduced network calls by 30%.
- · Extracted ORM manipulations with built-in cache mechanism. Reduced model codes by 50%.
- · Wrote hundreds of py.test fixtures and thousands of test cases. Improved code coverage by 20%.
- · Maintained tens of CI jobs within Jenkins.

Douban Book
Product Development Engineer

June 2012 - April 2013 Beijing, China

- · Participated on the rebuilding & refactoring process of *Douban Book*, which was visited by millions of users everyday. Decoupled this system from a monolithic one, to archive independent deployment.
- · Replaced PTL template engine with Mako. Reduced codes by tens of thousands of lines.
- · Implemented a system synchronizing product price and inventory from almost all e-bookshops in China, such as AmazonCN, Jingdong, Dangdang, etc. There were nearly 16 million+ subjects updating everyday.

EDUCATION

Jimei University

September 2008 - June 2012

Bachelor Degree in Software Engineering

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages Python, JavaScript, Java, C

Protocols TCP/IP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, WSGI

APIs REST, SOAP, JSON, XML

Databases MySQL, Postgres, InfluxDB, SQLite, Redis, MongoDB, BeansDB

Infrastructure as Code Kubernetes, Terraform, Ansible, Chef, Puppet Python Web Frameworks Flask, Django, Tornado, Quixote, Celery

Python ORMs DjangoORM, SQLAlchemy

Python Web Runtimes Supervisord, Gunicorn, uWSGI, Nginx

Javascript Frameworks Angular, React & Redux

VCS Git, SVN

CIs Jenkins, TravisCI, CircleCI Editors Emacs, Vim, SublimeText, Atom

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

SRL-Python A SimpleRegex implementation in Python.

fapistrano A Python port of Capistrano.

nim-markdown A markdown parser implemented in Nim-lang.

nim-mustache A mustache template engine implemented in Nim-lang.

beanstalk-clj A beanstalkd client for language Clojure.